<xocs:doc xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.elsevier.com/xml/xocs/dtd http://schema.elsevier.com/dtds/document/fulltext/xcr/xocs-article.xsd" xmlns:xocs="http://www.elsevier.com/xml/xocs/dtd" xmlns:cals="http://www.elsevier.com/xml/common/cals/dtd" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:ce="http://www.elsevier.com/xml/common/dtd" xmlns:sb="http://www.elsevier.com/xml/common/struct-bib/dtd" xmlns:tb="http://www.elsevier.com/xml/common/table/dtd" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ja="http://www.elsevier.com/xml/ja/dtd" xmlns="http://www.elsevier.com/xml/ja/dtd" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"><xocs:meta><xocs:content-family>serial</xocs:content-family><xocs:content-type>JL</xocs:content-type><xocs:cid>271074</xocs:cid><xocs:ssids><xocs:ssid type="alllist">291210</xocs:ssid><xocs:ssid type="subj">291682</xocs:ssid><xocs:ssid type="content">31</xocs:ssid></xocs:ssids><xocs:srctitle>The Lancet</xocs:srctitle><xocs:normalized-srctitle>LANCET</xocs:normalized-srctitle><xocs:orig-load-date yyyymmdd="20030922">2003-09-22</xocs:orig-load-date><xocs:available-online-date yyyymmdd="20030922">2003-09-22</xocs:available-online-date><xocs:ew-transaction-id>2010-04-03T22:12:44</xocs:ew-transaction-id><xocs:eid>1-s2.0-S0140673600509246</xocs:eid><xocs:pii-formatted>S0140-6736(00)50924-6</xocs:pii-formatted><xocs:pii-unformatted>S0140673600509246</xocs:pii-unformatted><xocs:doi>10.1016/S0140-6736(00)50924-6</xocs:doi><xocs:item-stage>S350</xocs:item-stage><xocs:item-version-number>S350.1</xocs:item-version-number><xocs:item-weight>HEAD-AND-TAIL</xocs:item-weight><xocs:hub-eid>1-s2.0-S0140673600X70262</xocs:hub-eid><xocs:timestamp yyyymmdd="20150514">2015-05-14T03:51:50.419687-04:00</xocs:timestamp><xocs:dco>0</xocs:dco><xocs:tomb>0</xocs:tomb><xocs:date-search-begin>19110128</xocs:date-search-begin><xocs:year-nav>1911</xocs:year-nav><xocs:indexeddate epoch="1064188800">2003-09-22T00:00:00Z</xocs:indexeddate><xocs:articleinfo>rawtext articleinfo crossmark dco dateupdated tomb dateloaded datesearch indexeddate issuelist volumelist yearnav articletitlenorm cid cids contenttype copyright dateloadedtxt docsubtype doctype doi eid ewtransactionid hubeid issfirst issn issnnorm itemstage itemtransactionid itemweight openaccess openarchive pg pgfirst pglast pii piinorm pubdatestart pubdatetxt pubyr sortorder srctitle srctitlenorm srctype vol volfirst volissue webpdf webpdfpagecount articletitle alllist content subj ssids</xocs:articleinfo><xocs:issns><xocs:issn-primary-formatted>0140-6736</xocs:issn-primary-formatted><xocs:issn-primary-unformatted>01406736</xocs:issn-primary-unformatted></xocs:issns><xocs:crossmark is-crossmark="0"/><xocs:vol-first>177</xocs:vol-first><xocs:volume-list><xocs:volume>177</xocs:volume></xocs:volume-list><xocs:iss-first>4561</xocs:iss-first><xocs:issue-list><xocs:issue>4561</xocs:issue></xocs:issue-list><xocs:vol-iss-suppl-text>Volume 177, Issue 4561</xocs:vol-iss-suppl-text><xocs:sort-order>66</xocs:sort-order><xocs:first-fp>281</xocs:first-fp><xocs:last-lp>282</xocs:last-lp><xocs:pages><xocs:first-page>281</xocs:first-page><xocs:last-page>282</xocs:last-page></xocs:pages><xocs:cover-date-orig><xocs:start-date>19110128</xocs:start-date></xocs:cover-date-orig><xocs:cover-date-text>28 January 1911</xocs:cover-date-text><xocs:cover-date-start>1911-01-28</xocs:cover-date-start><xocs:cover-date-year>1911</xocs:cover-date-year><xocs:title-editors-groups><xocs:title-editors-group><ce:title>Originally published as Volume 1, Issue 4561</ce:title></xocs:title-editors-group></xocs:title-editors-groups><xocs:document-type>converted-article</xocs:document-type><xocs:document-subtype>cor</xocs:document-subtype><xocs:copyright-line>Copyright © 1911 Published by Elsevier Ltd.</xocs:copyright-line><xocs:normalized-article-title>NOTESSHORTCOMMENTSANSWERSCORRESPONDENTS</xocs:normalized-article-title><xocs:attachment-metadata-doc><xocs:attachment-set-type>item</xocs:attachment-set-type><xocs:pii-formatted>S0140-6736(00)50924-6</xocs:pii-formatted><xocs:pii-unformatted>S0140673600509246</xocs:pii-unformatted><xocs:eid>1-s2.0-S0140673600509246</xocs:eid><xocs:doi>10.1016/S0140-6736(00)50924-6</xocs:doi><xocs:cid>271074</xocs:cid><xocs:timestamp>2010-10-04T19:03:02.533975-04:00</xocs:timestamp><xocs:path>/271074/1-s2.0-S0140673600X70262/1-s2.0-S0140673600509246/</xocs:path><xocs:cover-date-start>1911-01-28</xocs:cover-date-start><xocs:attachments><xocs:web-pdf><xocs:attachment-eid>1-s2.0-S0140673600509246-main.pdf</xocs:attachment-eid><xocs:ucs-locator>https://s3.amazonaws.com/prod-ucs-content-store-us-east/content/pii:S0140673600509246/MAIN/application/pdf/fcb9e0e5801504c4e9bd01db03ab4b88/main.pdf</xocs:ucs-locator><xocs:ucs-locator>https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/prod-ucs-content-store-eu-west/content/pii:S0140673600509246/MAIN/application/pdf/fcb9e0e5801504c4e9bd01db03ab4b88/main.pdf</xocs:ucs-locator><xocs:filename>main.pdf</xocs:filename><xocs:extension>pdf</xocs:extension><xocs:pdf-optimized>false</xocs:pdf-optimized><xocs:filesize>375479</xocs:filesize><xocs:web-pdf-purpose>MAIN</xocs:web-pdf-purpose><xocs:web-pdf-page-count>2</xocs:web-pdf-page-count><xocs:web-pdf-images><xocs:web-pdf-image><xocs:attachment-eid>1-s2.0-S0140673600509246-main_1.png</xocs:attachment-eid><xocs:ucs-locator>https://s3.amazonaws.com/prod-ucs-content-store-us-east/content/pii:S0140673600509246/PREVIEW/image/png/0d6d9df3d1dbdc440b08d9bf094fb998/main_1.png</xocs:ucs-locator><xocs:ucs-locator>https://s3-eu-west-1.amazonaws.com/prod-ucs-content-store-eu-west/content/pii:S0140673600509246/PREVIEW/image/png/0d6d9df3d1dbdc440b08d9bf094fb998/main_1.png</xocs:ucs-locator><xocs:filename>main_1.png</xocs:filename><xocs:extension>png</xocs:extension><xocs:filesize>113227</xocs:filesize><xocs:pixel-height>849</xocs:pixel-height><xocs:pixel-width>656</xocs:pixel-width><xocs:attachment-type>IMAGE-WEB-PDF</xocs:attachment-type><xocs:pdf-page-num>1</xocs:pdf-page-num></xocs:web-pdf-image></xocs:web-pdf-images></xocs:web-pdf></xocs:attachments></xocs:attachment-metadata-doc><xocs:refkeys/><xocs:open-access><xocs:oa-article-status is-open-access="0" is-open-archive="0"/></xocs:open-access></xocs:meta><xocs:rawtext>The Lancet Notes, Short Comments, and Answers to Correspondents.  A DIABETES CURE. A CORRESPONDENT recently submitted to us a diabetes cure with the request to have it examined. He was called to see a patient who had been taking it. She was unstable on her legs, excited, and had dilated pupils-symptoms which she attributed to the nostrum. It evidently consisted of the dried leaves of some herb. Submitted to analysis in THE LANCET Laboratory no alkaloid could be found, but there was a decided amount of tannin present and an aromatic oil. The curator of the Museum of the Pharmaceutical Society of Great Britain, Mr. E. M. Holmes, F.L.S., F.E.S., kindly examined the [quot]remedy.[quot] He expressed the opinion that it was Polygonum hydpo- piper, L., commonly known as water pepper. The fruits of Polygonum were, he states present, and although the few perfect leaves evident would do either for the spiral leaves of P. hydropiper or for the ordinary leaves of P. aviculare, the herb had the biting taste characteristic of water pepper. P. hydropiper is used for dropsy and P. aviculare for difficulty of passing urine, so that both would appear to have some action on the kidneys. According to W. T. Fernie, M.D. ([quot]Herbal Simples [quot]), the water pepper, or arsmart, grows abundantly by the sides of lakes and ditches in Great Britain. It bears a vulgar English name signifying the irritation which it causes when applied to the fundament; and its French sobriquet, culrage, conveys the same meaning:- [quot] An erbe is the cause of all this rage In our tongue called culrage.[quot] [quot]Fleas will not come into rooms where this herb is kept. It is used for curing proud flesh in the sores of animals, and the leaves serve the purpose of a mustard poultice. A piece of the plant may be chewed to relieve toothache, as well as to cure small ulcers of thrush in the mouth. It has been used in jaundice and cholera. Another polygonum, the great bistort, is strongly astringent, and has been used for a spongy state of the gums.[quot] The packet containing the remedy bore the inscription [quot]Van Veen and Co., Import van China and Japan, Amsterdam,[quot] and also an inscription written in Chinese characters. DEVONSHIRE SUPERSTITIONS. THE Bristol Times and Mirror states that in some parts of Devonshire a mother believes that if she imprisons a live spider in a nutshell and ties it round her infant's neck when the child is suffeiing from whooping-cough, that the disease will disappear when the spider dies. This newspaper remarks that a little girl went to a Tiverton shop- keeper and said to him, [quot] Will you please give mother a nut to put a spider in, as baby's got the whooping-cough.[quot] THE EASY SALE OF PISTOLS. THE ease with which the sale of pistols may be conducted without compliance with the provisions of the Act of Parliament which is supposed to regulate such transactions was exemplified recently in a prosecution at the Guildhall police court. The police at Canterbury found there a man in possession of a revolver and cartridges without a licence or permit to carry firearms. He was a perfectly respectable man, and he gave the police full information as to how. and where he purchased the revolver in London, with the result that proceed- ings were taken against Ernest Reeves, an assistant in the Anglo-Saxon Motor and Cycle Company, of Newgate-street. It was proved that the purchase was made without any of the prescribed formalities being observed at a branch establishment of the firm named, the defen- dant alleging that the customer came to see the goods, which had been obtained expressly for him from the head office, on Christmas Eve, just before closing-time ; that he said he would take them with him, and that in the pressure of business he was allowed to do so, instead of being referred to the Newgate-street establishment as intended by the defendant. An awkward circumstance for the defen- dant to explain was the fact that the bill given to the purchaser con- tained no mention of a revolver, the sum paid being described as for repairing a gun. This he sought to explain as a slip due to copying a similar entry of [quot]repair gun[quot] made already on the same day in the day-book. A fine of 085 was inflicted with the alternative of a month's imprisonment, the Alderman expressing regret that he could not make the punishment four times as heavy. APT HOSPITALITY. THE annual dinner to the coachmen and chauffeurs in the employ of medical men in Leicester took place at the De Montfort Hotel, Leicester, on Saturday, Jan. 21st. A hearty vote of thanks was passed to the medical men of the town for providing the necessary funds. THE Council of the Chelsea Hospital for Women states, for the informa- tion of any that may receive umuthorised appeals, that it has dis- continued the use of collecting boxes outside the hospital precincts. E. C. A. will find the answer to his question not very clearly given in the Medical Acts. The representation by an unqualified person that he is a duly registered practitioner is punishable. ERRATUM.-In our issue of Jan. 21st, p. 148, by a printer's error, Mr. R. F. Mann was referred to as photographer and assistant in the electrical department of the Willesden Hospital, instead of the Middlesex Hospital. COMMUNICATIONS not noticed in our present issue will receive attention in our next. - A DIARY OF CONGRESSES. THE following Congresses, Conferences, and Exhibitions are announced for 1911 :- Feb. 20th-25th (Cairo).-Fifth International Congress for the Blind. March 2nd-6th (Berlin).-Thirty-second Balneological Congress. [quot] 23rd (Paris).-First Congress of French Medical Journalists. April (Berlin).-German Surgical Congress. (Thirty-ninth Annual Meeting.) April 4th-7th (London).-Fourth Annual Nursing and Midwifery Conference and Exhibition. April 18th-20th (Paris).-Third Congress of Physiotherapy of French. speaking Physicians. [quot] 19th-22nd (Wiesbaden).-Twenty-eighth German Congress of Internal Medicine. [quot] 20th-22nd (Groningen).-Thirteenth Nature and Medical Congress. May 30th (The Hague).-International Congress on Opium. May (Washington).-Conference on the Protection of Industrial Property. (Question of False Marking of Goods.) May-October (Dresden).-International Hygiene Exhibition. May-October (London, Crystal Palace). -Festival of Empire Imperial Exhibition. (Profits to King Edward VII. Hospital Fund.) May-October(?) (London, Shepherd's Bush).-Coronation Exhibition. June (Paris).-First Congress of the International Medical Associa- tion for the Prevention of War. [quot] (Los Angeles, Cal.).-American Medical Association. June 5th-8th (Kolberg, Prussia).-Fifth International Congress of Thalassotherapy. June and July (Romford).-Town Planning and Modern House and Cottage Exhibition. July (Birmingham).-British Medical Association. July 24th-29th (Belfast).-Congress of the Royal Sanitary Institute. August 15th-21st (Dublin).-Royal Institute of Public Health. [quot] 30th-Sept. 6th (Portsmouth).-British Association. August or September (Berlin). [mdash] Third International Laryngo- Rhinological Congress. September (Brussels).-Exhibition of Fractures. [quot] (Turin).-International Congress of Pathology. [quot] (Genoa).-International Exhibition of Marine Hygiene. September-November (Antwerp).-International Exhibition of Ali- mentation, Brewing, Wines, and Liqueurs. Sept. llth-15th (Berlin).-National Congress for the Study and Pre- vention of Infantile Mortality (Gouttes de Lait). [quot] llth-16th (The Hague).-Thirteenth International Congress on Alcoholism. [quot] 18th-23rd (Sydney).-Australasian Medical Congress. [quot] 18th-24th (Turin).-Fourth National Congress of Hygiene. [quot] 24th-30th (Rome).-International Congress on Tuberculosis. [quot] 25th-29th (Rome) Seventh International Congress of Der- matology and Syphilology. October (Cologne).-International Congress of Criminal Anthro- pology. Oct. lat-4th (Li[eacute]ge).-Second Congress of Alimentation. Dec. 4th-9th (Havana, Cuba).-American Public Health Association. (Date not fixed) (Montreal).-Canadian Medical Association. (Date not fixed) (Rome).-International Exhibition of Social Hygiene. (Date uncertain) (Turin).-International Exhibition of Industry and Labour. In 1912 :- Spring (London).-Second Optical Convention. July (?) (Cologne).-International Congress of Nurses. September (Prague).-International Congress of Radiology and Medical Electrology. September (Berlin).-Sixth International Congress of Obstetrics and Gynaecology. [quot] Visit of German Medical Men to America. Nov. 22nd-29th (Washington, D.C.).-Fifteenth International Con- In 1913:- gress of Hygiene and Demography. In 1913 :- (London).-Seventeenth International Congress of Medicine. (London).-Historical Medical Exhibition. (Organised by Mr. Henry S. Wellcome.) (Dresden (?)).-International Conference on Cancer. (Washington).[mdash]Congress of American Physicians and Surgeons. August (Buffalo).[mdash]Fourth International Congress of School Hygiene. In 1914 :- (Vienna).-Third International Congress for Professional Diseases. In 1915 :- (London).-International Prison Congress. (London).-Imperial Exhibition (?) MEDICAL DIARY FOR THE ENSUING WEEK.                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                                 </xocs:rawtext><xocs:serial-item><converted-article version="4.5.2" docsubtype="cor" xml:lang="en"><item-info><jid>LANCET</jid><aid>00509246</aid><ce:pii>S0140-6736(00)50924-6</ce:pii><ce:doi>10.1016/S0140-6736(00)50924-6</ce:doi><ce:copyright type="unknown" year="1911"/></item-info><head><ce:title>Notes, Short Comments, and Answers to Correspondents.</ce:title></head></converted-article></xocs:serial-item></xocs:doc>